

# **OLGA VARENNIKAVA**

Communication & Graphic Designer

604-441-7424 olga.varennikava@gmail.com www.olgav.net

#### **ABOUT**

I've been working in the industry for the past 3 years and I'm very inspired how creative thinking and fresh ideas grab attention and cause a communication to be noticed and understood.

I'm proud to deliver logo designs, brand identities, promotional print and digital materials, web and UI/UX designs to connect businesses with their audience, communicate brands' messages in a memorable way, and to create a strong relationships through experience that reinforces the commercial and emotional value of the company.

## **SKILLS**

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4
- Responsive web design
- UI/UX design
- Photography
- Typography
- Colour theory
- Design rules & principles

#### **ATTRIBUTES**

- Creative, self-motivated & self-driven
- · Organized & detail oriented
- Hardworking & responsible
- Eager to learn & improve existing skills
- Have positive & optimistic attitude
- Speak English, French, Russian & Belarussian

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **GRAPHIC & WEB DESIGNER**

Paintshield Technology Corporation

March 2015-June 2016

- Designed logo and brand identity, collateral materials, marketing digital and print documents, presentational brochures and flayers, helping build up the business awareness on the market.
- Oversaw projects designed by design team assuring visual identity is consistent and is adherent to company's branding guidelines.
- Designed and developed company's website using designated CMS.
- Art directed and designed several social media promotional banners.
- Designed graphics for web site, blog posts, and promotional documents.
- Created website templates to be customized by company's clients.
- Did photo edits.

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

Privatis Technology Corporation

March 2014-June 2016

- Working both independently and closely with marketing team
   I was responsible of designing marketing promotional materials for
   web and print, ensuring that the visual identity follows brand standards.
- Designed marketing pitch presentation and various infographics in order to present complex data set in a simplified and visually engaging way to directly reach the core audience.
- Designed social media graphics and web banners using marketing best practices.
- Assisted in UI/UX design for company's Android application.
- Designed landing page, email campaigns and social media graphics to help promoting the app.

### COMMUNICATION DESIGNER

Freelance

June 2013-March 2015

- Designed logos and developed brand identities, helping companies to stand out among competitors.
- Designed brochures, banners, marketing documents, promotional flayers, booklets, eblasts for external clients.
- Consulted with clients to develop graphic pieces in order to meet the communication needs and to connect them with their customers.
- Did UI/UX design for Android application.
- Designed landing pages.
- Designed responsive website mockups.

# **EDUCATION**

### **DIPLOMA IN GRAPHIC DESIGN**

Visual College of Art and Design 20

Studied graphic design with focus on branding and advertising.

### **BACHELOR DEGREE IN TRANSLATION**

Minsk Linguistic University

2003-2008

Studied translation in written and oral form of communication. Major in simultaneous and consecutive interpreting and translation (French and Russian).